

Rayland Magalhães

Statistician Data Scientist



15 Sep 1994



Brazil Natal-RN



+55 (84)99467-2166



linkedin.com/in/rayland-csv/



magalhaes.estatistica@gmail.com

About me –

An Independent and self-motivated professional with excellent research and communication skills, enthusiasm to learn new things, always try to do its best in any work assigned and always tries to be appreciated as well-performer.

Skills ———

Statistics

Machine Learning

R

Python

Cloud Computing

SAS

SQL

Microsoft Office

C++

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Interests

Interested in new technologies, love to watch science-related content, and understanding how things work. One of my greatest inspirations is Adam Savage from MythBusters since he is always involved in projects that he loves and seems to have fun when facing new challenges.

Education

2016-2021 UFRN Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte

Bachelors in Statistics

Awards

2018 First position in the data science competition of the Statistics Depart-

ment of UFRN.

Projects

2021 Fraud Detection Algorithm

Developed a fraud detection algorithm to find irregularities in Brazil-

ian congressmen expenses.Unsupervised Learning

Outlier Detection

Data Visualization

· Approved by experts

2020 Pneumonia detection with Neural Networks

Developed my own neural network to detect pneumonia in chest X-

Rays

· Image processing

Feature extraction

Model training

· Parameter tuning

2020 Sentiment network analysis on Twitter

Developed an algorithm to extract tweets with a certain hashtag and

made a graph displaying the sentiment of each comment.

Data extraction with API

Graph theory

Sentiment Analysis

· Text processing

Regex

2018 Big Data Shiny App

Developed a shiny app to analyze expenses of Brazilian congressmen.

Massive dataset.

· Optimized data processing.

· Great data visualizations.

Easy to use and understand.

Work Experience

2019-2021 Upwork

Data Scientist

He worked on several projects in the most varied areas of knowledge and is one of the top rated freelancers on the platform with 100% job

success rate. (Click to visit profile)

2018-2019 Atle Consultoria

Internship

- Shiny apps development
- Report automation
- · Survey analysis
- · Buisness Intelligence